JARED MURPHY

DATA SCIENTIST

☑ jared.m.murphy@protonmail.com 📞 (904) 502-0547 👂 10910 Queens Blvd Apt 7J, Forest Hills, NY 11375

SUMMARY

I am a Data Scientist with a background in Mathematics and Statistics. I currently specialize in Time Series Analysis, and for my most recently completed project I used ARIMA modeling to test the validity of Covid-19 mortality data released by Johns Hopkins University and the CDC. I am currently in the final stages of completing a comprehensive technical analysis of the crypto-asset Bitcoin. In this project I compare the behavior of Bitcoins price action to that of several other asset classes and provide means for making long term forecasts for the future price of Bitcoin.

EDUCATION

University of North Florida June 2013 - Aug. 2015

B.S. Statistics 2015

Springboard Data Science Carreer Track Mar. 2020 - Jan. 2021

Intensive cousrse in data science, machine learning, Python and SQL

EMPLOYMENT

Self-Employed, Carpenter/Residential Painter, Hudson Valley, NY Oct. 2016 - Current

Finish carpentry, rough carpentry, drywall, concrete, residential painting

High School Equivalency Instructor, Dutchess Community College, Poughkeepsie, NY Mar. 2016 - Oct. 2016

Teaching high school math and science to students of all ages

Sales Associate, DSW, Jacksonville, FL Aug. 2010 - Aug. 2015

Customer service, shipping and receiving

SKILLS

DATA SCIENCE: Python, pandas, numpy, statsmodels, sklearn

MACHINE LEARNING: SUPERVISED LEARNING: KNN, Linear, Logistic, Multiple Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, SVM, Precision, Recall, Accuracy, F1, ROC

MACHINE LEARNING: UNSUPERVISED LEARNING: K-means Clustering, Hierarchical Clustering, Mean-Shift Clustering, PCA, Cosine Similarity

MATHEMATICS AND STATISTICS: Calculus I, II, III, Linear Algebra, Mathematical Statistics, Probability, Bayesian Methods, Hypothesis Testing, ANOVA

RELATIONAL DATABASES: SQL, MySQL, SQLite DATA VISUALIZATION WITH PYTHON: matplotlib

PROJECTS

Excess Deaths in United States Counties 02/01/20-10/31/20 (click title for link)

May 2020 - Nov. 2020

ARIMA modelling was used to forecast excess deaths in US counties during the time period of 02/01/20 to 10/31/20. Excess deaths were then compared with provisional deaths due to Covid-19 released by Johns Hopkins University and the CDC.

Bitcoin: A Technical Analysis (click title for link)

Nov. 2020 - Current

A comprehensive technical analysis of Bitcoins price action followed by a comparison of Bitcoin to other asset classes such as US sovereign debt, US equities., precious metals and commercial real estate.

AWARDS

Graduated Summa Cum Laude, University of North Florida

Aug. 2015

Inducted into Pi Mu Epsilon Mathematics Honors Society, Florida Eta Chapter

Aug. 2015

VOLUNTEERING

Kunzang Palchen Ling (Buddhist Center), Carpenter/General Contractor Red Hook, NY Ian. 2016 - Sept. 2019